Eslam Mohamed Moemen

Maadi, Cairo

eslammoemen@icloud.com

01002389382



in linkedin.com/in/eslammoemen

Summary

A Mobile Developer with experience in analysis, design, development, implementation and testing. Specialize in developing applications for the iOS platform with rich and intuitive GUI. Solid background of computer science and practical programming skills. a self-motivated, quick learner and a good team player.

Experience

Senior iOS Developer

Codes Roots

Jun 2022 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Supervising ECommerce iOS App Which Serving any Vendor Registration as SAAS and Designing its base Architecture With Multi Flavor iOS Concept which using .xcconfig files for each Sandbox and Production

- Leading, Supporting and contributing Functional Team
- Building Architecture for Large Scale Multi-flavor SaaS Software
- enhance Prototype Existence using CI/CD and automation for Deployment and Store Releases
- Splitting app to modules to deduce runtime and complexity using Modularization
- Quick Responds to hotfixes and maintain teammates's bad code

iOS Engineer

Codes Roots

Dec 2021 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Created, Modified and Managed SATA System which Consists of 3 iOS Native Apps SATA

Food(Services as Talabat), Delivery, Vendor and SATA Go App (Services as inDriver)

- implemented Food ,Go App in VIPER Architecture with Error Module Handler
- Connected Apps With Socket I.O and Web Socket as a live Order Cycle

iOS Engineer

Icosol Smart Technologies

Dec 2021 - Mar 2022 (4 months)

Responsible for Designing and Implementing Physio App

- Creating and Designing App From Scratch
- · Contributing with Back-end team to
- used MVVM Binding as a Design Architecture
- Applied SOLID Principles with Clean Code Concept
- · Integrated Push Notifications with firebase

iOS Engineer

EndPoint Software Solutions

Jun 2018 - Jan 2022 (3 years 8 months)

Designed and Developed Many Apps from Scratch and Uploaded them as a Software House Provider ,it contained medium functionality focused on business or consumer software.

- Designed All with iOS Patterns MVC,MVVM
- Included Source Control Git with GitHub
 Implemented Push Notifications with Firebase Cloud Messaging

iOS Developer

MYA Health Care

Jan 2020 - May 2020 (5 months)

- Developed and uploaded existing Project of Clinics and Appointment Reservations to the App-Store
- · Created and Integrated Apple Push Notification Certificates with Firebase Cloud Messaging

Skills

• Spatial Reasoning • Research Skills • Project Management • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • iOS Development • Data Structures • Native iOS (Swift) • Problem Solving • Interface Guidelines • API's integration (Codable) • Product Flavor Concept • iOS Deep Linking • Push Notifications, APIs and Cloud Messaging • Apple's Design Principles and application • UI/UX Designing • Ci/Cd • Git • Agile Methodology • SOLID • Swift Generics • Design Patterns (MVC, MVVM, MVP, VIPER) • Memory Management and Performance enhancement(ARC) • iOS LifeCycle • Associated Types • KVO • SnapKit • Google Maps • Firebase • CrashLytics • Analytics (Google,tiktok)

Education

Minufiya University

Bachelor's degree, Computer and Information Sciences, General 2015 - 2019

Projects

ECommerce APP

e-commerce app is a general platform for creating and generating multi vendor apps like pharmacies ,stores ,cloth shops ,malls etc.

Related Links

taqwa-foods: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/taqwa-foods/id6448988608

i7-store: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/i7-store/id6448677057

e-mart: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/e-mart-app/id6446054850

ximivog: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/ximivogueegvpt/id6446310604

Ninja-Foods: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/ninja-food/id6450151535

e-mashShop:https://apps.apple.com/us/app/e-mash-shop/id6446810453

cityRolls-store:https://apps.apple.com/us/app/city-rolls-store/id1660057793

SATA Food

is a service provided by sata technology group is to order and deliver food across cairo and nasr city ,choose your food offers from many categories add it to cart apply voucher or wallet and place order the app connected with vendor and delivery to track order status and delivery location

https://apps.apple.com/sg/app/sata-food/id1626062719

SATA Go

is a Service for people to get Rides, request ride from source to destination and get drivers offers and client choose whatever offer suitable checkin to destination checkout then pay visa or cash

Physio APP

This app is for Saudi Arabia's Health Ministry; it connects the therapist with patients across the kingdom; it includes patients to make requests to therapy sessions and also perform repeated planned visits.

Aakaber

App in UAE that provides different meat to buy or deliver to your place.

Weeding

Wedding offers you to select or view available Wedding Halls near you with a filtering option and provide a time Reservation.

Just Ask

is an app with 3 users: user and market or user and Provider, the provider makes service that is available to also Market can post or add products available to all users.

SagIny

Saglani app offers you a variety of services, including creating emails, creating resumes, as well as applying for jobs.

Made in Oman

The app Guide aims to satisfy both the Industrial and Commercial sectors with an ever-evolving platform targeted towards everyone from your local layman all the way to professional businessmen.

Sales

This App Provides shipment to all countries of the world at simple prices and guaranteed delivery.

e-Branch

shopping with e-branch you can order from categories and deliver from branches or home delivery.

Agar

you can sell or buy an apartment or land with agar the app offers you to place your advertisement in google maps in Saudi Arabia with very attractive UX.

Wash Squad

Wash Squad Provides Car wash and polishing service for your car

Give Me

It is interested in delivering all requests from restaurants, pharmacies and other stores, through the store search feature with one simple click, and then your order will reach the nearest representative to serve you.

My Care

My care app offers doctor's clinics and time of appointments with discounts for each doctor.

Testahl

testahl app is like a mini market to offer people what they need in different Categories.

Bokeh

you can send your loved ones a flower with this app that makes orders from florists across the kingdom.

Home Care

you can select the suitable care you need with a Home Care app by professionally trained nurses to offer elderly support or medical services.

Handbrake

is a car store to sell or offer your car in a big market with users to provide the best offer also you can buy your dream car.